# 

To be part of the success in an environment of growth and excellence so that, I can excel in my field through hard work, research and skills. Eager to learn new technologies with exposure. To explore myself with ideas and challenges to give my best.



Current Location: Chennai Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 1 Month(s)

Pref. Location: Chennai Notice Period: 15 Days or less

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming / Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: spring boot, java, java web services, rest, postgresql, mysql, oracle database, angularjs, bootstrap, html, css, front

end,backend,j2ee,sql,oops,jira,agile project management,ajax,core java

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 19-Jan-21 Last Modified: 19-Jan-21

### Summary

A techno-savvy with 4years of experience as full stack/ java developer. Worked on java, spring boot, JPA, hibernate, angularjs, bootstrap, Javascript, html, css. Successfully led key business initiatives & strategies to meet changing client needs/expectations, thereby resulting into high level of business improvement.

## Work Experience

Zebra Technologies as Software Engineer

Aug 2019 to Nov 2020

As a RWS(reflexis workforce scheduler) team member worked on different CR,PIR to improve product. Done bugs and issue solving on different product environments.

DataMetica as Engineer II Oct 2017 to Aug 2019

- \* Application development, designing, deployment and configuration management with agile methodology.
- \* Good hands on UI, design patterns, software design, software development, and combination of roles within the SDLC.
- \* Proficiency in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, bootstrap and common JavaScript Patterns.
- \* Strong coding and designing skills in Angular JS, Rest services.
- \* Understanding of communication between front-end of application with server side frameworks like SPRING MVC etc.
- \* Understanding of database query languages and DBMS like MySQL, PostgreSQL.
- \* Understanding of JAVA, spring boot, JPA, hibernate, WEB services.
- \* Performed Merging, Branches creation, managing users, Access control etc. using GIT.
- \* Handled deployments using Tomcat application servers.
- \* Perform the Bug fix, QA, DEV and PROD builds and deployed the artifacts on respective environment servers.
- \* Monitoring the deployments in all the environments.

#### Great West Global Business services India Pvt Ltd. as Software Developer Jun 2016 to Jun 2017

- Developed Responsive Sites using BootstrapJS.
- Developed Single Page Application where all the information that representative needs will be displayed in the same page
- Fetching and refreshing part of the screen using AJAX calls.
- Extensively used JQuery for handling events.

- - Involved in direct interaction and clarifications with the customer. Won team award and won codeathon competition held inside company

#### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from NIT Puducherry in 2016

#### IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience	
JAVA	1.8	2020	4 Year(s) 4 Month(s)	
JavaScript		2020	2 Year(s) 8 Month(s)	
HTML		2020	2 Year(s) 8 Month(s)	
CSS		2020	2 Year(s) 8 Month(s)	
Apache, jetty, web-logic, tomcat		2020	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
AngularJs		0	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
spring boot		0	2 Year(s) 8 Month(s)	
CORE JAVA		2020	2 Year(s) 8 Month(s)	
J2EE		2020	4 Year(s) 4 Month(s)	
JPA		2020	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	

## Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
Hindi	Expert			
Marathi	Expert			
Tamil	Beginner			

## **Projects**

Project Title: Social media analytics

Client: BSE

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Oct 2017 - Till Date Project Location: Pune Onsite / Offsite: Onsite

Role: Programmer Team Size: 3

Skill Used: Angularjs, Spring Mvc, Spring Boot, PLSQL, Bootstrap

Role Description: Full stack developer. Built this web application using postgres/PLSQL database, spring mvc and boot for

backend along with angularjs and bootstrap in front end.

Project Details: It uses angularJs as front-end development along with html, css, bootstrap, javascript. And spring MVC for back-end integration with java, postgres sql to store database information. This project analyses information which are in the form of website articles or facebook and twitter posts received by different users, affecting stock market BSE. The data is analysed by using different approaches. It is then presented to client to let him know, what affects his progressive business. This is a responsive website built for computers and laptops.

Project Title: client service application system

Client: CSAS/ Great west global Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jun 2016 - Jun 2017 Project Location: Banglore Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Programmer Team Size: 6

Skill Used: java, struts, Bootstrap

Role Description: Built a loan request screen using purely bootstrap along with struts framework.

Project Details: An application used in financial industry to track and let user have option to apply for loan( primary or mortgage). Its primarily focused on user ease to handle every request. Information regarding term, instalments all will be available for user. User can directly apply for it. If he has user privileges.

Project Title: Wifi- Spectrum analyser Client: College Final Year Project Nature of Employment: Full Time Project Location: NIT Puducherry

Duration: Apr 2014 - May 2015 Onsite / Offsite: Onsite

Team Size: 2

Role: Project Leader Skill Used: java, dbms, MySQL, HTML, Javascript, CSS, NetBeans, netsh tool

Role Description: I have collected different signals with its strength based on 2G/3G or WIFI or 4G. Used different devices to moderate signals. Such as laptops, android mobiles, routers, modems. To get better depiction of properties, we used NetSh tool.

Project Details: It is a web application. Used to detect WiFi signals and its other properties. Based on strength and quality a graph will be resulted which is used to choose signal. Factors which affects a signal are listed out. And for different SSIDs different spectrum will be produced. Which helps user to have clarity on signal. And help user to choose one.

#### **Affirmative Action**

#### **Work Authorization**

Category: OBC - non-creamy

Physically Challenged: No

Countries: India

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time